









ABOUT 0

Software Developer with 4 years of experience in Java, based Software/Web Application with strong analytical and problem-solving skills with demonstrated analysis solve complex problems with high efficiency and writing Quality Coding, Testing, Documentation in the areas of Development and Maintenance.

SKILLS X

Programming Language: Java, Python

Tool and Framework: Spring Boot, Spring ORM, Hibernate, Spring Data JPA, JUnit, Mockito Spring Batch, Kafka, Elastic Search, Redis

Database: Oracle, MySQL, MongoDB

Cloud: Azure (API Gateway, Function, LogicApp, Blob, VM), AWS (EC2, ECS, S3, RDS)

Operating System: Windows, Linux

Build and Deployment Tool: Jenkins, Docker, Openshift.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CITICORP SERVICE INDIA PRIVATE LIMITED, PUNE, INDIA / Programmer Analyst 2, Sep, 2020 – Present Technologies used: Java, Elastic Search, Spring Boot, Spring Batch, Hibernate, No SQL, SQL (Oracle), Cache (Encache).

Smart Search Product

- Developed search related API'S from starch for large scale system (~1M Request/min).
- Developed core functionality as per user preferences search using elastic search with low latency.
- Independently worked on requirement gathering and design and implementation of core functionality.
- Developed Tree Search filter using Breath first search Algorithm.
- Improved batch processing time (from 4 hour to 2 hour) from SQL DB to Elastic Index.
- Written JUnit for the services using Mockito with 100% coverage.

Common Inbox Dashboard

Technologies used: Java, Kafka, Spring Boot, Spring Batch, Hibernate, No SQL, SQL (Oracle), Cache (Redis)

- Developed Common Inbox Dashboard using asynchronization message processing system using Kafka.
- Developed core functionality to convert entitlement of user.
- Implemented Custom Validation for Producer message which prevent from unwanted message.
- Developed batch process to archive message according to custom logic in real-time.

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICE PRIVATE LIMITED, CLIENT: TATA STEEL EUROPE | System Engineer, July,2017 - Sep,2020

Technologies used: Java, XSLT, WSDL, Azure Cloud, Business Process Model

- Design and Developed an application for automatic failure notification through call service using Python and Flask web-service which made a profit of 5-10% increase in overall business.
- Developed Java libraries for commonly used component like HTTP Connector, JSON to XML Parser, CSV to XML Parser.
- Developed server less API's using Azure Function integrated with Azure API gateway.
- Migration from monolith architecture to micro service architecture deployed in cloud using Azure Pipeline.
- Developed Supply Chain process using BPM Tool to integrate with different application.

PROJECTS 🕞

Healthy Food | JAVA, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Amazon S3, Orcale 19c

Design and Developed server-side Restful API'S for application using spring boot and security with JWT Token implementation.

Flood Fill Algorithm / JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Developed Web Application to demonstrate the internal work of MS-Paint using Breath First Search algorithm.

Snap Chat Feature | Python 3, Keras, OpenCV

Developed an AI algorithm which include face filter.

EDUCATION

Orissa Engineering College, Orissa, India Bachelor of Technology: Electrical Engineering Aug, 2013-May, 2017 7.9 CGPA

ACCOMPLISHMENT 🛣

- Appreciation Certification from Tata Steel client for automation of legacy services.
- Achieving excellence in project delivery.